Martin O'Brien Johnson

mobjohnson@gmail.com cell: (703) 677-2953 www.mobjohnson.com

Full-Stack Web Developer who approaches challenges with the experience of an Engineer. Driven with an expectation of excellence, I receive satisfaction by solving complex problems systematically. I enjoy the process of collaboration, the value of diverse talents and believe growth results from learning and experimenting.

Skills

- **Technical:** Ruby, Git/ Github, RSpec, PostgreSQL, Ruby on Rails, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, iQuery, Underscore.js, Backbone.js, Handlebars.js, D3.js and C3.js.
- Creative: Developing user stories, ERDs and wire framing; and utilizing Agile Development.

Education

General Assembly 2014

Web Development Immersive August-October: 12 week immersive experience Back End Web Development May-July: 10 week part-time course

 Full-stack web development programs focused on common best practices in object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and test-driven development. Developed a portfolio of individually focused and collaboratively focused projects.

University of Florida 1999

Bachelor of Science in Civil Engineering

Experience

ADTEK Engineers 2007-2010

Vice-President of Civil Engineering/ Civil Department Manager

Accomplishments:

- Successfully implemented training for and progressive development of comprehensive three dimensional site plan design using Civil 3D, allowing more cost-effective accommodation of revisions.
- Created Quality Assurance Field Review resulting in fewer critical problems during construction.

William H. Gordon Associates 1997-2007

Director of Engineering

Responsibilities:

- Managed land development projects including residential, commercial, transportation, recreational, industrial, institutional and public projects in DC metro area.
- Collaborated on Planning, Architectural, Landscape Architectural, Environmental, Surveying, Traffic Engineering, Geotechnical and Land Use Attorney requirements.

Marquez, Hall and Johnson/ G. L. Marquez & Associates 1986-1997

Partner/ Department Manager, Project Manager, Project Engineer, GIS Developer *Accomplishments*:

- Developed Alachua, FL, Street Addressing Project using AutoCAD and AutoLISP.
- Developed, initiated and managed Sumter County GIS using progressive development/ programming in and multiple translations between AutoCAD and Arc/Info.